# Ali Yazdi

Dept. Computer Engineering Amirkabir University, Hafez Ave., Tehran, Iran ma.yazdi75@gmail.com • ma.yazdi75@aut.ac.ir • (+98) 912 037 1375 • https://aliyazdi75.github.io

#### ABOUT ME

I have been working as a Flutter developer and mobile team leader for two years. I am a CS graduate who interests in using Artificial Intelligence and Software Engineering in my work. I am an open-source advocate who helps developers to solve their problems in development. I am finding a better opportunity and willing to relocate to the new country.

## WORK EXPERIENCE

Mate Machine Inc., North Vancouver, British Columbia, Canada - Remote

Jun 2020 - Present

Flutter

Preparing the Flutter application for the first launch.

Tarafdari, Tehran, Iran

Mar 2019 - May 2020

Flutter, Drupal, Laravel, MySQL

- Working as mobile application team leader at one of the most popular sport social media.
  - Developing requirement APIs.
  - R&D about Flutter framework and migrating the android application to Flutter application that is including multimedia content, live score matches, sports TV streaming with live chat on the socket.

### **EDUCATION**

### Amirkabir University of Technology, (Tehran Polytechnic), Tehran, Iran

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Engineering, Software

Sep 2015 – Jan 2020

- Thesis: Designing and Implementing Location Based Social Network Recommendation System
- Adviser: Prof. Mohammad Rahmati

### Adab High School. Tehran, Iran

• GPA: 19.31 / 20.00

Diploma in Mathematics and Physics

Sep 2011 – Jun 2014

## HONORS & AWARDS

• First Place in the 12th Iran Web and Mobile Festival (IWMF)
For the Best Sport Mobile Application among 7k applications

Feb 2020

- Most installed sport application in Iran
   May 2020
   In my first job, we could reach more than 200k active users on the Google Play Store after migrating to the flutter
- Ranked in top 0.2% among more than 180K participants

  In Nation-Wide University Entrance Exam among all Iranian Student of Physics and Mathematics

  Jul 2015
- Qualified for the Second Round of Olympiad among more than 70K participants
   In the Iranian Physics Olympiad and Mathematical Olympiad

## **PUBLICATIONS**

#### **MEDIUM**

- [1] <u>A. Yazdi</u>, "The Software Engineering approach in Cross-Platform Programming with Flutter (part 1)", Using Software Engineering methods to design and build a fully responsive and adaptive mobile, desktop, and web application, *Flutter Community*, Jan 2021.
- [2] <u>A. Yazdi</u>, "The Software Engineering approach in Cross-Platform Programming with Flutter (part 2)", Designing and building the Flutter application structure using the Bloc pattern in the micro-service architecture, *Flutter Community*, Jan 2021.
- [3] A. Yazdi, "The Software Engineering approach in Cross-Platform Programming with Flutter (part 3)", Designing and building the Flutter application data models and backend using the Build value and Bloc pattern, *Flutter Community*, Jan 2021.

## PROFESSIONAL PROJECTS

■ The Flutter Protfolio Application, Flutter

Designing and Building a responsive Flutter gallery application for any platform.

■ The Flutter Gallery Application, Flutter

Designing and Building a responsive Flutter gallery application for any platform using micro-service architecture.

■ The Flutter Media Notification Plugin, Java, Flutter

Designing and Building a Flutter Plugin that helps developers to show their media notification and control streaming media beyond their Flutter application.

■ The Location-Based Recommendation System, Django, Django Rest Framework, Scikit-learn, Flutter Designing and Implementing Location Based Social Network Recommendation System with Djando and Flutter.

## RESEARCH INTERESTS

- Artificial Intelligence
- Machine Learning
- Software Engineering

## RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Artificial Intelligent and Robotics Lab, Amirkabir University of Technology,

Oct 2019 - Oct 2020

- Undergraduate Research Student, Science Department
  - Project: Designing and Implementing Location Based Social Network Recommendation System
  - Supervisors: Prof. Mohammad Rahmati
  - Focus: Artificial Intelligence, Software Engineering, Data Analytics

#### **LANGUAGES**

- Persian: Native language
- English: Fluent, working proficiency

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

## Programming Languages

Dart, Python, Java, C/C++, PHP, Assembly

## ■ Mobile Development

Flutter, Android

### ■ Database Systems

PostgreSQL, MySQL

## Operating System

Linux (Ubuntu)

## ■ Web Development

Django, Django Rest Framework

#### Other

Microcontroller Programming, Bash Scripting

## ACADEMIC PROJECTS

#### ■ **Programming Languages**, racket

NUMEX-Interpreter: Designing a simple interpreter NUMEX programming language with Racket.

### ■ **Information Security**, *python*

My-Security-Course: Encryption with MD5, SHA256, DES, working with cryptool software nmap and using ms08\_067 exploitand.

### ■ Computer Networks, python

DNS-UDP-TCP-Proxy: A python proxy that receives HTTP packets on UDP then sends them on TCP with DNS server.

## ■ Microprocessor & Assembly Language, C

Digital-Watch-with-LCD: A digital watch with LCD and alarm using microcontroller ATMEGA16.

### ■ Data Structure & Algorithms, Java

Finite-State-Machine: Creating four types of data structure and searching using AVL-tree, balance-TST, trie-tree and hash.

#### ■ Advanced Computer Programmings, Java

Planet-vs-Zombies: A 2d game similar to Plant vs Zombies game using java object oriented programming.

[Last Update on 2021-01-11]